Guide to the Gould family papers, 1799-[ca. 1869]
Gould family papers, 1799-[ca. 1869]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gould family papers, 1799-[ca. 1869]
2033
Gould family.
3.4 cubic ft.; 9 v.; 8 o/s flds.; 6 reels microfilm.
Diaries, letters, family papers, genealogical charts, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Diaries, 1799-1832, of Stephen Wanton Gould, concerned with meetings of the Society of Friends, the activities of his family members and friends as well as several public events; extracts from the records of monthly meetings, 1676-1707, held by Rhode Island Quakers; letters, 1862-1868, from John Stanton Gould to his daughter Mary (Gould) Baldwin, relating to the Goulds and the related families, Gould's early life, his interests, and other personal matters; journal, 1866-1869, showing Gould's interest in cattle diseases and grasses, prison reform and other humanitarian aims, and containing many references to his public life and his role in the founding of Cornell University; and microfilm copies of a typewritten copy of a diary, 1851-1862, kept by John Stanton Gould's second wife, Hannah Wright Gould (1819-1912); and Gould family genealogical charts and notes compiled by her granddaughter, Dorothy C. Abbott, including data on related families.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Stephen Wanton Gould (1781-1838) was a clockmaker in Rhode Island. John Stanton Gould (1810-1874), his son, was a New York State legislator, agriculturist, Cornell University trustee and non-resident faculty member.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Diaries, 1799-1832, of Stephen Wanton Gould, concerned largely with meetings of the Society of Friends in and around Newport, R.I., but also mentioning the activities of his son John Stanton Gould and other family members and friends as well as several public events; extracts from the records of monthly meetings, 1676-1707, held by Rhode Island Quakers, copied and annotated by Gould; letters, 1862-1868, from John Stanton Gould to his daughter Mary (Gould) Baldwin, relating to the history and genealogy of the Goulds and the related Mott, Rodman, Stanton, and Wanton families, Gould's early life, his interest in the antislavery and temperance movements and in scientific agriculture, and other personal matters; journal, 1866-1869, showing Gould's interest in cattle diseases and grasses and in prison reform and other humanitarian aims and containing many references to his public life and his role in the founding of Cornell University; and microfilm copies of a typewritten copy of a diary, 1851-1862, kept by John Stanton Gould's second wife, Hannah Wright Gould (1819-1912), concerned largely with her life in Hudson, Columbia County, N.Y., and with reflections on religion; and Gould family genealogical charts and notes compiled by her granddaughter, Dorothy C. Abbott, including data on the related Atterbury, Bakewell, Gilpin, Gregg, Lawton, Newton, Parker, Rodman, Wanton, and Wright families.
Also, Hannah Wright GOuld diary (1851-1862) and Stephen Gould diary(1807-1809). Also, various and numerous legal documents.
Also, documents collected by a granddaughter of John Stanton and Hannah Wright Gould, these papers include a Radclyffe (Radcliffe) family indenture, and estate settlement documents and other papers (1687-1747) of the Dyer, Slocum, and Gould families of Newport, Rhode Island; a letter from Father Sebastien Rasles (Rale) concerning the Abnaki Indians and the Protestant missionary to the Indians, the Reverend Joseph Baxter; statistics on the population of Rhode Island together with the quantity of arms and ammunition in private hands, prepared by Governor Stephen Hopkins (1756); a letter (December 1764) to an unnamed person from Charles Bowler, collector of His Majesty's revenues in Newport, protesting Governor Hopkins' defense of the rights of the colonies; a compilation of silver prices from 1700 to 1764 "from the Boston Records," and a copy of a report (ca.1777) on the trial of the Rev. William Dodd at Old Bailey, London; a copy of a petition (October 1777) signed by John Townsend and Gideon Wanton and directed to Sir Peter Parker, admiral of the British navy, concerning their confinement on a prison ship in Newport Harbor; other Townsend family papers; an undated letter from Daniel Holloway, a Newport seafarer; also, printed copies of the Articles of the United Fire Club of Newport with signatures added (1783) and the act to incorporate Newport as a city (1784). Also, the journal (1812) of Thomas Wright, Mrs. Stoddard's great-grandfather, kept during his return to England.
Also, extensive correspondence and other papers (1824-1943) of the Goulds, Stoddards, and related families, including religious correspondence of Sarah Sherman (1832); letters to Julia E. Sanford (later Mrs. Goodwin Stoddard, Hannah Gould's mother-in-law) while she was a student at the Brooklyn Heights Seminary; and notes (1902) to Hannah on her engagement to Sanford; many travel letters, including those written (1901) by Hannah when she accompanied her parents, Benoni and Annie Gould Johnson, and her sister Hilda to Switzerland, England, and Scotland, one (ca.1901) from an American art student describing her living quarters, studies, and companions in Paris, and two (1902) from a college friend, Mary B. Lewis, on a tour of Japan and China, giving details of her excursion by mule litter to the Great Wall, others from Hannah and Sanford Stoddard from the British Isles (1911), from Hannah's aunt, Elizabeth Wright Gould Berry, and her cousin Harriet, written chiefly from Florence, Lausanne, and Munich (1913); approximately 100 "round robin" letters (1908-1920) written by former members of the White Lodge at Smith College, telling of their activities following graduation and presenting a cross section of opinions on such issues as woman suffrage and the position of women, the League of Nations, and progressive education and a record of their involvement in Red Cross work and food conservation during World War I and in social betterment groups.
"Round robin" letters include some from Anna Speck Thomson concerning her teaching at the Settlement School in Hindman, Kentucky, and at Oklahoma College for Women, Chickasha. Also, scattered estate settlement papers (1847-1906); correspondence (1919) between Sanford Stoddard and George P. McLean, Senator from Connecticut; bylaws, minutes, and memoranda (1925-1925) of the Bridgeport Committee for Mental Hygiene, the constitution and bylaws of the College Club of Bridgeport; and other typescript and printed items pertaining to Mrs. Stoddard's devotion to child training and welfare, literary studies, and other educational and civic matters; also, one letter (1943) from her cousin, Romyn Berry, concerning family history and current news, genealogical notes, and obituary clippings; and one box of photographs of friends and family members. Also, a series of pen and ink drawings by Hendrik Willem van Loon, in which he caricatures literary and historical figures.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gould family.; Atterbury family.; Bakewell family.; Baldwin, Mary Gould.; Gilpin family.; Gould, Hannah Wright, 1819-1912.; Gould, John Stanton, 1812-1874.; Gould, Stephen Wanton, 1781-1838.; Gregg family.; Lawton family.; Mott family.; Newton family.; Parker family.; Rodman family.; Stanton family.; Wanton family.; Wright family.; Cornell University--History.; New York (State). Legislature.
Subjects:
Society of Friends.; Quakers--Rhode Island--Newport.; Family--Rhode Island.; Family--New York (State); Antislavery movements.; Temperance.; Agriculture.; Cattle--Diseases.; Grasses.; Prison reformers.
Places:
Rhode Island--Religious life and customs.; New York (State)--Politics and government.; Hudson (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Columbia County (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Genealogies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collections #2034, #2054, #2556, 2558, #2592.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. English Documents
  - Indenture (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Document 1: John Bradstaugh, 1598
  - Legal document (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Document 2: 1598
  - Indenture, 1630 (Folder 2)
    Document 3: between Paull Greenwood of Hundersfield and Zachary Fielden, February 13, 1630
  - Indenture, 1633 (Folder 3)
    Document 4: between Paule Wydoppe of Sangfield and John Greenwood and Richard Thomas, November 16, 1633
  - Will, 1637 (Folder 4)
    Document 5: last will and testament of Richard Horsfall
  - Court document, 1637 (Folder 5)
    Document 6 re will: lands, pastures, appurtenances between John Horsfall and John Waite, Henry Horsfall and Isabell his wife and Robert Greenwood and Mary his wife and Robert Partinson and Elizabeth his wife,
  - Notice of Marriage, 1666 (Folder 3)
    Document 7: William Fielden of Hundersfield and Judeth Greenwood, January 19, 1666
  - Indenture, 1668 (Folder 6)
    Document 8: between Robert Heywood of Heywood and sisters and brothers of John Lafland and Richard Armitage of Leeds and Raphe Lamer of Hundersfield, November 10, 1668
  - Indenture, 1668 (Folder 4)
    Document 9: between Robert Hoywood and Richard Armitage, November 10, 1668
  - Indenture, 1690 (Folder 5)
    Document 10: between Elizabeth Radcliffe of Great Moarley and Ambrose Greenwood of Hollingworth
  - Indenture, 1691 (Folder 4)
    Document 11: between Ralph Hill of Hollisworth and Ambrose Greenwood of Hollisworth, June 18, 1691
  - Deed or Indenture, 1698 (Folder 2)
    Document 12: between Ambrose Greenwood of Walsden and Benjamin Stock of Hundersfield
  - Indenture, 1698 (Folder 6)
    Document 13: between Benjamin Stock of Hundersfield and Ambrose Greenwood of Walsden, March 14, 1698
  - Indenture, 1699 (Folder 4)
    Document 14: between Philipp Storke of Tathdale and Ambrose Greenwood of Hundersfield, May 9, 1699
  - Document, 1699 (Folder 4)
    Document 15: re debt paid: between Benjamin Stock and Ambrose Greenwood of Hollingworth within Wallsden, May 11, 1699
  - Will, 1716 (Folder 7)
    Document 16: Ambrose Greenwood of Hollingworth, June 20, 1716
  - Legal Document, n.d. (Folder 2)
    Document 17: statement of payment of debts: Ambrose Greenwood of Walsden signed by Robert Sutcliffe
  - Legal Document, 1726 (Folder 2)
    Document 18: statement of payment of debts: Ambrose Greenwood of Walsden signed by Thomas Fielden
  - Will, 1749 (Folder 2)
    Document 19: Nathan Kirshaw, November 13, 1749
  - Indenture, 1744 (Folder 5)
    Document 20: between John Greenwood of Sangfield and William Greenwood of Sangfield and Ambrose Greenwood of Sangfield re discharge of sum of five shillings
  - Accounting, 1782 (Folder 2)
    Document 21: James Jackson accounting statement to Ambrose Greenwood, January 3, 1782
  - Opinion, 1785 (Folder 2)
    Document 22: Robert Parker re Wm. Greenwood's will, Ap. 22 '85
  - Indenture in Three Parts, 1788-1789 (Folder 2)
    Document 23: between Ambrose and John Greenwood of Sangfield andThomas Butterworth of Ssenshaw within Walsoon and John Hoff of Brick Oven within Stansfield, August 26, 1788; concerning loans and rents, final date, February 19, 17989
  - Indenture, 1792 (Folder 7)
    Document 24: between John Greenwood of Sangfield, Ambrose Greenwood of Sangfield and Thomas Firth of Stones, June 17, 1791
  - Indenture, 1793 (Folder 7)
    Document 25: between John Greenwood of Sangfield and Elihu Dickinson of Sighflatts, July 30, 1793
  - Agreement, 1810 (Folder 2)
    Document 26: between Joseph Wright of Sheffield and Benjamin Wilson of Manchester, John Bramley of Halifax, and James Hoyle of Hollins Mill, for sum of 1664 pounds
  - Agreement, 1823 (Folder 2)
    Document 27: between William Wright of Sheffield and Samuel Greenwood of Stores, January 29, 1823
  - Case, 1834 (Folder 2)
    Document 28: William Greenwood estate re Ambrose Greenwood and trustees, March 29, 1834
  - Further Case, 1834 (Folder 2)
    Document 29: "The copy case herewith sent was prepared by the Solrs of the vendor for Mr. Cootes's opinion." re estate of Wm. Greenwood and disposition to Ambrose Greenwood, August 27, 1834
  - Legal document (Folder 8)
    MISSING - Document 30: [Hollingworth]
  - Indenture (Folder 8)
    MISSING - Document 31: [Hollingworth]
  - Indenture (Folder 8)
    MISSING - Document 32: [Hollingworth]
  - Legal document (Folder 8)
    MISSING - Document 33: [Hollingworth]
  - Lease, 1752 (Folder 9)
    Document 34: John Van Rensselaer to Thomas Van Alstyne, Albany County, September 16, 1752
  - Deed, 1782 (Folder 9)
    Document 35: Phineas Gilbert and wife to James Gould, Newport, Rhode Island. Recorded June 16, 1783
  - Document, 184? (Folder 10)
    Document 36: Philip Schuyler, Albany - William Van Alstyne, Hudson, Signed January 17, 1792 and recorded at Hudson, New York, 184? (on vellum)
  - Indenture, 1829 (Folder 9)
    Document 37: (counterpart of lease), Benjamin Marshall of Hudson to Roderick R. Hunt, Hudson, Columbia County, New York. August 3, 1829
  - Indenture, 1834 (Folder 9)
    Document 38: Jeremiah Van Rensselaer et al to Joseph Marshall of Stockport, Columbia County, New York, November 24, 1834
  - Certificate, 1869 (Folder 9)
    Document 39: April 5, 1869, suspends James De Long and appoints William A. Gould as Consul of the United States of America at Aux Cayes, Haiti, recorded October 22, 1869
  - Certificate, 1870 (Folder 9)
    Document 40: recognition of appointment by government of Haiti, April 5, 1870
  - Chart, post 1888 (Folder 9)
    Document 41: genealogical chart
  - Indenture, 1598 (Folder 1)
    Document 42: Charles Radclyff of London, County of Lancaster, and Henry Radclyff, heirs and assigns and Richard sale of house and land called Hollingsworth.. ., 1554
  - Land transaction, 1687 (Folder 1)
    Document 43: Samuel Dyre of Boston ? sum of two hundred pounds "New England money" for delivery ? Charles Dyre of Rhode Island, a certain parcel of land in Newport, signed by S. D., 10/5/1687 and Ann Vernon, mother of S. D., 10/28/1687
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Letter from Sebastien Râle, 8/17/1718 (Box 1, Folder Env. 1)
    August 17, 1718, Narantsonak [Norridgewock], Maine (in French); also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Benjamin Franklin Letter, 7/22/1756 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Letter to the editors of the Massachusetts Magazine containing a copy of the letter, July 22, 1756, from Benjamin Franklin to a Miss Hubbard re death of his brother John
  - Thomas Wright Correspondence, 1812-1846 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Letters to and from Thomas Wright: from cousin Bakewell, 1812; letters to wife Sarah and children (including Hannah) while abroad, 1834; from cousin Bakewell, 1846
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Letters, 1814-1830 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Letters from Stephen Wanton Gould: to Aunt, 1814; letter of introduction to Samuel Marriot of Hudson, New York for John Stanton Gould, 1827; to Aunt Anna,1830
  - John Stanton Gould Correspondence, 1830-1870 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes: Stephen Gould letter to his Aunt Anna, 1831; "NYS Institution for the Blind" letter, 2/6/1868, where J. S. Gould resigns as Member of the Board; Library of Congress - Copyright Office
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1832-1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    To Sarah Sherman, 1832 (2 letters); to Hansie (Annie Gould), 4 April 1877; postcard to Mrs. B. S. Johnson, Jan. 6, 1882; to Emily, Oct. 3, 1896
  - Letters to Hannah Wright Gould, 1834-1881 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    From her father, Thomas Wright, 1834; husband, J. S. Gould, including from Niagara Falls, Cornell University 1851-1874
  - Letters to John Stanton Gould, 1842-1872 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    From his mother Hannah Rodman Gould, 1842, 1843, 1844; including letter to him when Mary Ashby Gould (1st wife) died, 11/22/1843; W. S. Leavitt Report re Cornell; letter from J. W. Hague to J. S. Gould, 1872
  - Letters to Hannah Wright Gould, 1863-c.1881 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Small notebook: "A Journal of childhood of son Romeyn and daughter Harriet, July 1882-October 1884?; from female friends and relatives: one letter to Mother from Rebekah, 1870; one from T.(?) Leavitt, 1874; tintype of unidentified couple in envelope attached to handmade booklet of poetry copied by Mary E. Mack, cover reads "Elizabeth W. Berry from her loving Mary E. Mack?; letters to and from Elizabeth Wright Gould
  - Elizabeth Wright Gould Correspondence, 1868-1918 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    To and from Elizabeth Wanton Berry (Lizzie), Olive, Children
  - Letters from John Stanton Gould, 1871-1872 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    To children from Ithaca, one mentions President White giving his wife a pin valued at $700
  - Letters to Hannah Wright Gould, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Condolences on the death of J. S. G. and resolutions of Cornell Board of Trustees - 2 letters from A. D. White
  - "Barbara Frietchie" Items and John Greenleaf Whittier Letters, 1872-1886 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    2 "Barbara Frietchie" items: 1 official record from pastor of E. V. R. Church, Frederick, MD.; one newspaper clipping, 1869; 2 John Greenleaf Whittier letters, 1886
  - Hannah W. Gould Correspondence, 1856-1872 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    One letter from John on Cornell stationery
  - Letters to Dr. J. Romeyn Berry and His Family, 1869-1891 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Condolences on the death of his first wife, numerous church resolutions concerning Rev. Berry throughout his career, letters of condolence to his family after his death in 1891, formal church resolutions regarding his death and giving tribute to his long service to the Reformed Church
  - Julia E. Sanford Correspondence, 1873-1889 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Correspondence from prior to 1875 to 1889
  - W. Bogardus Berry and Son, Romeyn Berry Correspondence, 1883-1889 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Letters to or from W. Bogardus Berry and son, Romeyn Berry
  - Genealogy, No date (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Miscellaneous file of genealogical materials, H. G. J. Stoddard
  - Bound Volumes of Letters, 1862-1868 (Box 2)
    2 volumes entitled: "Letters on the History of the Gould Family to Mary W. G. Baldwin (J. S. G.'s second daughter by Mary Ashby) by John Stanton Gould"; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Bound Volumes of Letters, 1862-1868 (Box 3)
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1900-1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Miscellaneous letters 1900-1942
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    European Tour, June 1-September 10, 1901
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Letters addressed to "Hans" (Hannah Johnson) regarding her engagement to Sanford Stoddard, January 18-May 31, 1902
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Trip to England and Scotland, September 12, 1911-January 2, 1912
  - Mrs. Elizabeth Berry and Daughter Harriet Correspondence, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Trip to Europe, May 27-September 25, 1913 and n.d.
  - Harriet G. J. Stoddard Letters, 1913-1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    From Mr. and Mrs. Benoni Johnson (parents of H. G. J. S.) from trips to Europe, Florida, and California, December 12, 1913-December 26, 1920
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Sanford Stoddard correspondence re League of Nations, 1919
  - Hannah Gould Johnson Letter, [1908] (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Hannah Gould Johnson getting into Alpha Sorority
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1908-1910 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    White Lodge round robin letters, February 18, 1908-June 18, 1910
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1910-1912 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    White Lodge round robin letters, July 18, 1910-August 14, 1912
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1912-1915 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    White Lodge round robin letters, August 16, 1912-September 8, 1915
  - Hannah Johnson Stoddard Correspondence, 1916-1920 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    White Lodge round robin letters, September 11, 1916-September 16, 1920
  - Postcards, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Hopi Indians, some filled out, but never mailed, Annie Gould Johnson
  - Postcards, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Mt. Vernon souvenir package; Smith College - Greene Hall; golf course, St. Andrew's, N.B.; Rome
- Series III. Diaries
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1799-1803 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    November 1799-October 16, 1803; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1803-1804 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    October 17, 1803-May 4, 1804; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1804 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    May 5, 1804-October 18, 1804; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1804-1805 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    October 23, 1804-May 31, 1805; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1805 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    June 1, 1805-December 31, 1805; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1806 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    January 1, 1806-May 1, 1806; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1806 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    May 3, 1806-December 30, 1806; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1807 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    January 1, 1807-July 23, 1807; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1807-1809 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    July 24, 1807-April 30, 1809; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1809-1812 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    May 1, 1809-June 30, 1812; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1812-1815 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    July 1, 1812-August 20, 1815; only on microfilm, (original not held by this library) see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1815-1823 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    August 24, 1815-September 25, 1823; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1823-1829 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    October 2, 1823-March 6, 1829; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1829-1832 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    April 1, 1829-December 31, 1832; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1833-1836 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    January 1, 1833-August 28, 1836; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Stephen Wanton Gould Diary, 1836-1838 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    September 1, 1836-September 20, 1838; also on microfilm, see Series 7
- Series IV. Other Writings: journals, volumes, lecture notes, sermons
  - Records, 1676-1707 (Box 10)
    Quaker meeting records from Rhode Island, copied by Stephen W. Gould from old meeting records
  - Journal, 1812 (Box 10)
    "A brief diary of where I was on every day. In my visit to England, in 1812"; Thomas Wright's return to England the year after he emigrated
  - Journal, 1823 (Box 10)
    "Almanack for 1823"
  - Journal, 1824 (Box 10)
    Diary of John S. Gould, October 26, 1824-3 Mo. 1827, includes 12/1755 account of people in Colony of R.I. - whites and blacks together
  - Journal, 1847-1850 (Box 10)
    Journal of Residence at Albany; also on microfilm, see Series 7
  - Journal, 1866-1869 (Box 10)
    John Stanton Gould Journal, 11/1/1866-12/19/1869
  - Travel Journal, 1931 (Box 10)
    Miss Avery, November 4, 1931
  - Volume, 1922 (Box 10)
    Small account notebook (A. A. U. W.?)
  - Volume, 1924 (Box 10)
    A. A. U. W., New Haven, February 16, 1924
  - Volume, 1821 (Box 11)
    John Stanton Gould, "Began to cipher," April 3, 1821
  - Volume, 1840 (Box 11)
    Excerpts, July 20, 1840
  - Volume, 1850 (Box 11)
    Bible, Hannah Wright, August 1850
  - Volume, 1874 (Box 11)
    H. W. Gould, small notebook with metallic clasp
  - Volume, 1890 (Box 11)
    Our Birthdays, Hannah G. Johnson, December 16th, 1890
  - Volume, 1915 (Box 11)
    Hannah J. Stoddard, Xmas, 1915; quotes
  - Volume, 1928 (Box 11)
    Avery, '28-'30; lecture notes
  - Volume, 1935 (Box 11)
    Ancestral Tablets, book of genealogical chart forms
  - Volume, n.d. (Box 11)
    Excerpts, "Most Protestant sects are built on Papal foundation
  - Volume, n.d. (Box 11)